mabelandmoxie.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy — Livingly Media

Last Updated: December 6, 2019

 **We take the privacy of our users very seriously.**  Please read this Privacy Policy to learn more about how we treat personally identifiable information. We provide this Privacy Policy because you have a right to know what information we collect, how it is protected and used, and the circumstances under which it may be disclosed. If you have comments, suggestions, questions, or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us via email at [dpo@livinglymedia.com](mailto:dpo@livinglymedia.com) or in writing at: Privacy Director, Livingly Media, Inc., 201 Redwood Shores Parkway, Suite 300, Redwood City, CA 94065.

 **Online Privacy Standards.**  While there are limited official standards governing privacy practices on the internet, we follow the principles supported by the Federal Trade Commission’s Fair Information Practices Principles, currently available at https://www.ftc.gov/reports/privacy-online-fair-information-practices-electronic-marketplace-federal-trade-commission and the Data Protection Act 1998 and Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of the 27th of April 2016, General Data Protection Regulation referred to as “GDPR”.

 **What This Policy Covers.**  This policy covers Livingly Media’s treatment of personally identifiable information that we obtain when you visit our website or use our services. We regard personally identifiable information as information that someone can use to identify or contact you in person, such as real name, telephone number, birth date, email address, or physical mailing address. 

**What This Policy Does Not Cover.**  This policy does not cover the privacy practices of third parties that we do not own or control, such as our partners and advertisers. In addition, we may provide links to other services and on occasion to other sites that may interest you. All of these sites operate independently of Livingly and they have their own privacy or security practices. For your best on-line experience, we encourage you to review their policies before submitting any personal information to them.

## HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION

INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE

 **Registration Information.**  During the email newsletter registration process, we collect your email address. Pursuant to the CAN-SPAM act of 2003, you may unsubscribe from our email newsletters at any time by using the unsubscribe link contained in the emails.

## INFORMATION WE DO NOT COLLECT

 **Children.**  As explained further in our Terms of Service, currently available at http://www.livinglymedia.com/terms-of-service/, you must be 13 years of age or older to register to use our website. Therefore, we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information about children. If you believe that we have information from or about anyone under 13 years of age, please notify us by email at dpo@livingly.com or write to our Privacy Director at the address noted above.

 **Social Security Number or Credit Card.**  We do not ask for or require your social security number or credit card to use any of our services or to access any part of our site.

## INFORMATION WE TRACK

 **Log Files.**  Similar to many websites, we gather certain anonymous, non-personal information automatically and store it in web server log files. This information includes internet protocol addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), site entry/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to improve our site, analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movements around the site, and gather aggregate information about our user base as a whole. Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of services or members from which individual member identities have been removed, and therefore does not include your personally identifiable information.

 **Cookies.**  A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. It can also help us understand how our site visitors click to our site, and what pages they view during their visit. Similar to many websites, we store an encrypted cookie on your computer so we can remember you when you come back to our website without requiring you to log-in every time. Cookies also allow us to track and understand the interests of our users to enhance the overall experience on our site.

 **Our partners.**  Some of our business partners may also use cookies on our site. For example, some of our advertising partners may use cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information about your visit to our site in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. We have no access to or control over these cookies, and, as noted above, this privacy policy does not govern the use of cookies by our business partners or advertisers. To be excluded from these services, please visit some of our partners’ websites and follow the instructions provided.

  *  **Google:**[ http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

  *  **Quantcast:**  http://www.quantcast.com/docs/display/legal/Opt-out+of+Quantcast+Delivery

  *  **Network Advertising Initiative:  **http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp

 **You can set your web browser software to disable cookies**. To do so, please refer to the help section of your specific browser for more information on how to manage or disable cookies. If you disable cookies, you may still view our site, but some areas of our site will not work properly.

## HOW WE USE INFORMATION

 **In Company Communications**. We use emails and/or prominent notifications on our websites as our primary means to inform our members of important service and promotional announcements.

 **Service-related Announcements.**  We use your email address to deliver important service-related announcements. Example service-related announcements include: email verification during registration, requests for password reset, important security or server maintenance updates, software updates, upgrades, and new releases, or policy changes. These service-related announcements are considered a fundamental part of our web service, and members cannot opt-out of these email announcements.

 **Promotional Announcements.**  In order to improve the experience for our users, we will offer you the ability to sign up for optional email communications, such as regular updates from our corporate website, or email alerts and newsletters for specific web guides. These communications are enhancements to our service and are entirely optional. We will ask for your consent before sending you promotional communications, and will make it easy for you to unsubscribe from these communications, either through the emails or though your member profile page.

 **Site Statistics.** As noted above, we use information collected from our web log files to calculate and publish anonymous, non-personal, aggregate statistics that we believe our members are interested in viewing. For example, we track and publish the total number of users who have viewed a particular web page. We publish this data in aggregate form only, and do not tie it to any personally identifiable information.

 **For internal reporting and analysis.** As noted above, we use information gathered from log files and cookies to improve our site, analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movements around the site, and to gather aggregate information about our user base as a whole. We do not tie this data to personally identifiable information.

## HOW WE SHARE AND DISCLOSE INFORMATION

WITH THIRD-PARTIES

 **Sharing, Renting, and Selling Information We Collect.**  We will neither rent nor sell your personally identifiable information to anyone. Occasionally we share anonymous, non-personal, or aggregate information about our user base with partners or advertisers, and we may publish these aggregate usage statistics on our website for the interest of our members. We do not tie this shared or published data to personally identifiable information.

AS NECESSARY IN LEGAL CIRCUMSTANCES

 **Legal Requirements.**  We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

## HOW WE KEEP INFORMATION SECURE

 **Security of Account Information.**  Your account information is password-protected. We will not share your password with anyone. Please do not share your password with anyone, and remember to change your password from time to time, to keep your account information secure.

 **Network Security.**  We have implemented a variety of commercially standard security technologies and procedures to protect information, including your personal information, stored in our computer systems from unauthorized access. Please be aware that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, thus we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, but we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

 **Management Procedures.**  We also maintain standard physical and electronic procedural safeguards that limit access to your personally identifiable information to our employees (or people working on our behalf and under confidentiality agreements) who, through the course of standard business activities, need to access your personally identifiable information.

## YOUR PERSONAL CHOICES

 **Receiving Communications.**  If you subscribe to any optional promotional communications, you will be able to unsubscribe from through the emails we send you.

 **Editing / Deleting Member Account Information.**  You can view information we may have collected from you during a user registration process in a member profile page, where you can add, edit, or delete it as you see fit. You may also request deletion of your member account by emailing [dpo@livinglymedia.com](mailto:dpo@livinglymedia.com).

## FOR EU DATA SUBJECTS - LEGAL BASIS FOR COLLECTING AND USING YOUR DATA

 **This section tells you the legal bases we use to collect and use your data:   **

Account creation and Profile    
Basis: Contract 

Advertising     
Basis: Legitimate interest when serving advertising using non-personalized mode through our ad server; Consent when serving advertising using personalized mode through our ad server and with our header bidding partners

Content Delivery Network (CDN)  
Basis: Legitimate Interest 

Contests and Surveys  
Basis: Consent 

3rd Party Cookies, Pixels, and Measurement    
Basis: Consent   

Livingly Media Cookies and Measurement Using Internal Software    
Basis: Legitimate Interest 

Newsletters    
Basis: Consent 

Information, system, network and cybersecurity    
Basis: Legitimate Interest 

## FOR EU DATA SUBJECTS - HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR DATA? 

We delete or anonymise your data held in our archives unless retained through Consent, Contract, or Legitimate Interest.  Occasionally personal data is kept for longer than our standard retention policy, if it is required for legal or safeguarding interests or in order to respond to any complaints or claims that you make. If this is the case, we will only keep the data for as long as we need in order to fulfill those purposes. 

You have the right to exercise choice/Consent and the possibility to review and change Consent choices at any time. To do so, please email [dpo@livinglymedia.com](mailto:dpo@livinglymedia.com) or use the following links for each of our websites. Please note, on some browsers, you may need to use the ‘reload’ button on your browser after visiting the link below, in order to load the form:

The consequence of your choosing not to provide Consent is that Livingly Media will not call the relevant pre-selected advertising partners services on our webpages for your device after the choice has been made. The consequence of your revoking Consent is that Livingly Media will no longer call our pre-selected advertising partners services on our webpages for your device after Consent has been revoked.

You have the right of access, rectification, to be forgotten, portability, to withdraw and the right to object to us processing your personal data for the purposes set out above at any time. Unless we can show that we have a Legitimate Interest to continue processing your personal data, we will stop processing it.   

You can delete your account at any time and/or choose to anonymise your posts by contacting us at [support@livingly.com](mailto:support@livingly.com) or [dpo@livingly.com](mailto:dpo@livingly.com), and you can unsubscribe to newsletters and surveys on your Profile or by unsubscribing using the link at the bottom of every email. 

## FOR EU DATA SUBJECTS -  DATA PROTECTION OFFICER

The Data Protection Team for Livingly Media can be contacted by emailing [dpo@livinglymedia.com](mailto:dpo@livinglymedia.com). 

## FOR EU DATA SUBJECTS -  COMPLYING WITH THE LAW 

We are complying with the Data Protection Act 1998 and Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of the 27th of April 2016, General Data Protection Regulation referred to as “GDPR”. 

## FOR EU DATA SUBJECTS -  COMPLAINTS TO THE SUPERVISORY AUTHORITY 

You have a right to complain to the Information Commissioner's Officer (ICO), which regulates data protection compliance in your country, if you are unhappy with how we have processed your personal data. You can do this by visiting the relevant [ICO's site](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/).  

## UPDATES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

 **From time to time, we will review and make changes to our privacy policy.**  When we do so, the most recent version of our privacy policy will become available from a link on our homepage and here.
